<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joël Roman Ky</title>
    <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joël Roman Ky</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joelromanky.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_09_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_09_05/</guid>
      <description>Our paper NeurIPS’22 Cross-Domain MetaDL Challenge: Results and lessons learned got accepted at Proceedings of Machine Learning Research (PMLR) NeurIPS 2022 Competitions Track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_07_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_07_12/</guid>
      <description>Participation at the 28th IEEE Symposium on Computers and Communications (ISCC 2023) in Gammarth, Tunisia from July 9 - July 12, 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_07_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_07_05/</guid>
      <description>Our journal paper ML Models for Detecting QoE Degradation in Low-Latency Applications: A Cloud-Gaming Case Study got accepted at IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_05_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_05_19/</guid>
      <description>Our conference paper A Hybrid P4/NFV Architecture for Cloud Gaming Traffic Detection with Unsupervised ML got accepted at 28th IEEE Symposium on Computers and Communications (ISCC 2023), Gammarth, Tunisia, July 9 - July 12, 2023.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_02_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_23_02_17/</guid>
      <description>Our journal paper An Analysis of Cloud Gaming Platforms Behaviour Under Synthetic Network Constraints and Real Cellular Networks Conditions got accepted at Journal of Networking and Systems Management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 16:23:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/awards/</guid>
      <description>Research honors and awards      Prizes at Cross-Domain MetaDL: Any-Way Any-Shot Learning Competition with Novel Datasets from Practical Domains part of NeurIPS 2022 Competition Track.  First prize in Meta-Learning league  Certificate   First prize in New-in-ML league  Certificate   Second prize in Participants of a Rarely Represented Country league  Certificate     Best poster and presentation award at the 10th TMA PhD School colocated with Network Traffic Measurement and Analysis Conference (TMA), Enschede, Netherlands, 2022  Certificate    High-School awards      Best score in National High School Diploma (Baccalauréat Série C in french) 2016, Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso Bronze Medal in Panafrican Mathematics Olympiads (PAMO 2015), Abuja, Nigeria  Certificate   Bronze Medal in Panafrican Science Olympiads (PASO 2015), Abuja, Nigeria  Certificate   Best score in National College Certificate (Brevet d&amp;rsquo;études du premier cycle in french) 2013, Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_11_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_11_04/</guid>
      <description>Participation at the 18th International Conference on Network and Service Management (CNSM 2022) in Thessaloniki, Greece from October 31 - November 04, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_10_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_10_28/</guid>
      <description>Team MetaCD² got awards at the NeurIPS&#39;22 competition track Cross-Domain MetaDL: Any-Way Any-Shot Learning Competition with Novel Datasets from Practical Domains presented in NeurIPS 2022 Competition Track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_09_09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_09_09/</guid>
      <description>Our workshop paper Assessing Unsupervised Machine Learning solutions for Anomaly Detection in Cloud Gaming got accepted at Workshop on High-Precision, Predictable, and Low-Latency Networking (HiPNet &amp;lsquo;22) colocated with 18th International Conference on Network and Service Management (CNSM), Thessaloniki, Greece, October 31 - November 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_06_30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_06_30/</guid>
      <description>Participation and poster presentation at the 10th TMA PhD School colocated with Network Traffic Measurement and Analysis Conference (TMA) in Enschede, The Netherlands from June 27-30, 2022.
Best Poster award for the poster presentation Characterization and troubleshooting of cloud gaming applications on mobile networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_04_28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_22_04_28/</guid>
      <description>Participation in the days of the GDR RSD at Rennes, France and presentation entitled Protocol for measuring the transmission opportunities of a variable capacity network and its use from April 27-28, 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_21_11_17/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/news/news_21_11_17/</guid>
      <description>Start a PhD (under CIFRE contract) between Orange Innovation and University of Lorraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/papers/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 18:36:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/papers/papers/</guid>
      <description>Journal papers Conference/Workshop papers Posters Internship reports  Journal papers       📃 ML Models for Detecting QoE Degradation in Low-Latency Applications: A Cloud-Gaming Case Study
 Joël Roman Ky, Bertrand Mathieu, Abdelkader Lahmadi, Raouf Boutaba IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management, Special Issue on Robust and Reliable Networks of the Future, 2023. Impact Factor: 5.3 (2023). DOI Paper Code    📃 An Analysis of Cloud Gaming Platforms Behaviour Under Synthetic Network Constraints and Real Cellular Networks Conditions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/projects/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 14:44:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/projects/projects/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/blog/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 14:44:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/blog/blog/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:42:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/experience/</guid>
      <description>Orange Innovation     November 2021 - Now
PhD CIFRE - Research Engineer
Lannion, France
Vitesco Technologies     April 2021 - September 2021
Machine Learning Research Intern
Toulouse, France
 Research internship in academic collaboration with ANITI (Artificial and Natural Intelligence Toulouse Institute), IMT (Institut de Mathématiques de Toulouse) and LAPLACE (Laboratoire Plasma et Conversion d&amp;rsquo;Energie) State of the art of the modeling of PEM fuel cells Prototyping of Machine Learning models for Remaining Useful Life estimation  SII Group     December 2020 - March 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:42:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/education/</guid>
      <description>](/images/ut3.jpg)-- Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science     October 2021 - Now
University of Lorraine
Nancy, France
 Title : Automatic characterization, classification and troubleshooting of cloud gaming applications Doctoral School : IAEM - Lorraine Laboratory : LORIA Research Team : RESIST Supervisors :  Isabelle CHRISMENT, Professor, University of Lorraine Raouf BOUTABA, Professor, University of Waterloo Abdelkader LAHMADI, Associate Professor, University of Lorraine Bertrand MATHIEU, Senior Researcher, Orange Innovation    Master of Science, Computer Science     September 2020 - September 2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:42:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/skills/</guid>
      <description>Coursework 📖      Computer Science 1. Software programming 2. Distributed programming 3. OS, Networks &amp;amp; Security 4. Web programming    Machine Learning 1. Supervised Learning - Linear models - Support Vector Machines - Decisions Trees - Random Forests - Ensemble Learning 2. Unsupervised Learning - Clustering (K-means, Gaussian mixtures) - PCA (Linear, Kernel, Sparse) - Self-Organizing Maps    Deep Learning 1. Neural Networks (ANN, DNN, CNN, RNN, GAN, Auto-Encoders) 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 11:21:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joelromanky.github.io/bio/about/</guid>
      <description>Bio Research interests News Professional Experience Education Awards Skills  Bio     Hello 👋,
I am a PhD Candidate in Computer Science from University of Lorraine and an Engineer 🎓 graduated from Toulouse INP-ENSEEIHT in Computer Science and Telecommunications 💻.
I did my preparatory classes at CPGE Mohamed V in Casablanca, Morocco. I went to a special high school, a military one 👮‍♂️, the Prytanée Militaire de Kadiogo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
